<resources>
    <string name="app_name">10 Best Folding Knives of 2019</string>
    <string name="overview">The folding pocket knife is something of an institution among outdoorsmen the world over but it’s not just used for boning fish and opening stubborn tins around the campfire anymore. Today it’s must-have equipment for police and other first responders, rescue crews, climbers, delivery persons, and craftspeople. And let’s not forget that it’s also an increasingly popular means of self-defense in an increasingly dangerous world. The one thing all pocket knives have in common is their utter practicality. Though they have myriad applications they’re able to be toted about in your pocket just like loose change.</string>

    <string name="bt1">
Safer than Karambit knives and more convenient than a Spyderco knife, the Kershaw Blur Knife is our best choice of folding and pocket knives you’ll currently find on the market. For everyday use in a variety of situations, you’re unlikely to find anything better that will perform as reliably as this.\n\n
It boasts a corrosion-resistant blade that maintains its edge despite heavy use, while the stainless steel locking line adds to its strength and security to minimize – and hopefully eliminate any danger when using it. This makes it an ideal knife for hunting, tactical situations, camping, and industrial environments and are also useful as a day-to-day knife to have around the house.\n\n

⚫Key Features:\n

◾ SpeedSafe and thumbstud allows for quick, safe, and easy release  \n
◾ Stainless steel locking liner riveted inside handle adds strength and security\n
◾ Pocket clip for easy storage and portability\n
◾ Pre-drilled holes in handle for straightforward change of clip position or knife carrying side\n
◾ Corrosion resistance ensures longevity and high performance\n

⚫Specification: \n\n
    ◾Brand – Kershaw\n

</string>

    <string name="bt2">
If you’re looking for one of the best budget tactical knives that also works as an excellent and effective knife for other situations, the Gerber Paraframe Mini Knife is perfectly compact, lightweight but also reliable, with a rugged design that – on first glance – may deceive. \n\n
This design ensures durability and quality for longevity and continual high performance. The secure stainless steel handle also delivers safety when not in use with an open frame lock mechanism while also being easy to carry and deploy. As for maintenance, it’s super simple to clean, even despite the handle-window design, meaning you can use it time and again without the risk of rusting and corrosion. Like any knife, though, we’d still recommend taking as much care as possible to guarantee edge retention and parts functionality, and this one is a little more of a challenge to sharpen than other, more expensive options. \n\n

⚫ Key Features: \n

◾ Rugged and reliable design ensures durability and quality\n
◾ Ideal for a variety of applications and situations including military, tactical, and industrial\n
◾ Secure stainless steel handle and clip ensures safe transportation\n
◾ Fine-edge blade is lightweight and easy to clean\n
◾ Safe and easy to open frame lock design\n

⚫ Specification: \n\n

◾    Brand - Gerber\n
◾   Model22-48485\n
◾   Weight3.2 ounces\n

</string>

    <string name="bt3">
A knife that looks like it should cost way more than it does while also making you look at feel like the badass you always knew you were destined to be, the Smith and Wesson SS Assisted Folding Knife delivers high-quality performance in a variety of environments. Immediately, you’ll see the blade is durable and robust, being crafted from 4034 Blade Oxide High Carbon Stainless Steel that ensures excellent performance and longevity, regardless of whether you use it a lot of a little.

If you prefer your knives to have weight to them, this is an excellent option without being too heavy you feel bogged down when strapped to you. If you’re moving around either through work or through the woods on your monthly camping, this knife is great for fast, easy access thanks to its convenient pocket clip. \n\n

⚫ Key Features: \n

◾ Durable blade made from 4034 Blade Oxide High Carbon Stainless Steel\n
◾ Quick and easy access with convenient pocket clip\n
◾ Flipper/finger actuator and M.A.G.I.C assisted opening\n
◾ Liner lock security ensures protection when carrying\n
◾ Ambidextrous thumb plate ensures preparation for any situation\n\n

Specification: \n

◾    BrandSmith and Wesson\n
◾    ModelSWMP4LS\n
◾    Weight7.5 ounces\n

</string>

    <string name="bt4">
Fans of the Benchmade pocket knife will find the Mini Griptilian 556 Knife is yet another fantastic option in a long line of equally remarkable products. Aesthetics is often overlooked in items such as knives, but this sleek and modest design is very much what guides people towards it, and the fantastic performance that combines both functionalities with simplicity is what keeps them using it.
The high-quality American steel ensures top quality edge retention, which minimizes maintenance, something that’s especially good news for everyone who loves everything about their knives except for cleaning them, although as we keep saying (and shouldn’t have to) clean your knives, guys. \n\n

⚫ Key Features: \n

◾ Perfect combination of simplicity and function for optimum performance\n
◾ First-rate edge retention and corrosion resistance through high quality American steel\n
◾ Strong and versatile for any situation and application\n
◾ Full ambidextrous handle ensures comfortable grip and preparedness\n
◾ Axis locking mechanism provides safety with easy open and closing\n\n

⚫ Specification: \n

◾    BrandBenchmade\n
◾    Model556BK\n
◾    Weight2.81 pounds\n

</string>

    <string name="bt5">
The CRKT Squid Folding Pocket Knife is as stylish as it is easy-to-use and great for anyone looking for a casual knife to carry around on weekends out or just to have around the house in case they need to show off how prepared they are. The black stonewash finish is simple, and it casts of expectations other tactical knives by delivering only what you need.
With on-blade friction, you’re guaranteed a secure grip when sheathed in the handle, with the frame lock giving you further peace of mind. It holds the edge much better than other knives of a similar price, even with everyday use. You may not need to use it every day, but if you do, the low-profile pocket clip attaches it firmly and discreetly, yet still simple to take out at a moment’s notice. \n\n

⚫ Key Features: \n

◾ On-blade fiction grooves provide secure grip\n
◾ Low-profile pocket clip for easy, discreet carrying\n
◾ Black stonewash finish is both simple and stylish\n
◾ Frame lock feature ensure safety when not in use\n
◾ Limited lifetime warranty\n\n

⚫ Specification: \n

◾    BrandColumbia River Knife and Tool\n
◾    Model4008075\n
◾    Weight 6.4 ounces\n

</string>

    <string name="bt6">
As far as lightweight automatic knives go, the Ontario RAT Folding Knife is an excellent option that delivers several carrying possibilities to suit your needs in whatever you’re going. You can adjust the 4-way pocket clip for easy access wherever you are and while the lanyard holes may be a little too large for you to carry it like you would keychain knives, you’re still getting versatility with portability options you don’t get with every knife out there.
As for when you need to use it, the ergonomic handle is comfortable to hold to maintain superb grip and purchase with everything from opening boxes, prying lids, and in emergency situations. The spine jimping feature provides a level of control that may surprise you, and it could easily displace more expensive knives as the favorite in your collection. We wouldn’t blame you, either. \n\n

⚫ Key Features: \n

◾ Open post construction allows easy cleaning for maintenance and longevity\n
◾ Ergonomic nylon handle and spine jimping ensures excellent design with great control\n
◾ 4-way position pocket clip and lanyard holes for versatile carry options\n
◾ Liner lock mechanism ensures safety and protection\n
◾ Thumbstud provides easy one-handed opening\n\n

Specification: \n

   ◾ Brand Ontario Knife\n
   ◾ Model8846\n
   ◾ Weight5 ounces\n

</string>

    <string name="bt7">
The Buck QuickFire Assisted Opening Folding Knife delivers high-speed efficiency with a fast-releasing blade that’s as effective in one hand as it is the other. Using a dual spring mechanism, it deploys quickly but safely to guarantee you don’t injure yourself (or others) when releasing it in situations at home, at work, or out and about.

The blade quality also ensures longevity, and its razor-sharp blade almost eliminates the need for knife sharpeners and decreases maintenance, guaranteeing high performance for longer than you may be used to. When not in use, the midlock found in the handle keeps the blade from springing out unexpectedly, and if it did, you’d be the first to know about it, while the deep-pocket carry clip is discreet and reliable. \n\n

⚫ Key Features: \n

◾ Razor-sharp and versatile blade with excellent strength, edge retention, and corrosion resistance\n
◾ One-handed, ambidextrous opening with quick-fire ASAP technology\n
◾ Dual-spring ensures fast but safe blade release\n
◾ Midlock design and rotating blade ensures safety and security when carrying\n
◾ Deep-pocket carry clip makes transportation easy\n\n

⚫Specification: \n

◾    BrandBuck\n
◾    Model0288BKS\n
◾    Weight1.6 ounces\n

</string>

    <string name="bt8">
Our pick for the premium pocket and folding knife in the world is the Benchmade North Fork Knife which boasts high-quality steel that provides comfort in holding, carry, and using while delivering unrivaled results. The blade is perfectly balanced and maintains a fantastically sharp edge while also being resistant to rust even under heavy, consistent use.
It’s also easy to carry and will fit awesomely in your pocket with your money clip, car keys or zippo lighter without feeling too bulky and cumbersome. If want to ensure you can reach it whenever, you can take advantage of the pocket clip which is reversible to suit both left- and right-handed dudes. The manual opening ensures protection and is easily operated with a single hand so you can save the day in a flash. \n\n

⚫ Key Features: \n

◾ High quality CPM-S30V steel is well-balanced with excellent edge retention and rust resistance\n
◾ Stabilized wood handle more resistant to environmental damage than other materials\n
◾ Lightweight and comfortable design to easy use anywhere and in any situation\n
◾ Reversible clip pocket for ultimate accessibility\n
◾ Manual knife with easy one-handed closing and opening\n

⚫ Specification: \n\n

◾    BrandBenchmade\n
◾    Model15031-2\n
◾    Weight3.16 pounds\n

</string>

    <string name="bt9">

This multifunctional SOG Money Clip Pocket Knife is a far sight better than the cheap pen knives of your youth and will amaze you at how useful it can be. The compact design makes it super easy to carry and store, but still serves you well when called upon in a variety of situations.
The 2 ounce stainless steel handle is well constructed, with no loose bolts or connections, ensuring safety and showing fantastic craftsmanship at a wonderfully reasonable price. The design may put some of you off, as the gaps and windows could make it easy to catch on pockets, rivets, or your belt, and make it a challenge to clean, but its deceivingly small size this isn’t as much as an issue as you may think. \n\n

⚫ Key Features: \n

◾Compact design with wide functionality for a variety of everyday situations\n
◾2 ounce stainless steel handle is comfortable to carry and hold\n
◾Satin-polished stainless steel tough enough to handle camping environments\n
◾One-hand open and liner lock system makes it easy to open and safe to store\n
◾Razor-sharp edge retention and corrosion resistance\n

⚫Specification: \n\n

◾    BrandSOG\n
◾    ModelEZ1-CP\n
◾    Weight2.08 ounces\n

</string>

    <string name="bt10">
Our final pick is a superbly effective, efficient, and high-performing knife inspired by the Land of the Rising Sun. It boasts handmade D2 tool steel that ensures durability and reliability and maintains a sharp knife edge even despite everyday use. The beveled design also ensures smooth cutting, so if you want to show off and use as a razor, you’ll get a face without razor bumps, we probably wouldn’t recommend this, though.
The bamboo style handle comes with a pocket clip for easy, secure carrying, but if you don’t want to use that, you can take advantage of the nylon sheath. KATSU Handmade Steel Japanese Folding Knife is also a great way to store it when at home and allows you to keep it safe and in one place. If you use multiple knives on trips, it’s also useful for stopping you having too much stuff in your pockets and means you only have to expose it to the elements when called upon. \n\n

⚫ Key Features: \n

◾ Handmade D2 tool steel knife with extra sharp double bevel blade\n
◾ High quality nylon sheath ensures protection and easy portability\n
◾ Traditional Japanese style thumb notches with one hand opening lever\n
◾ Bamboo-style handle with pocket clip attached ensures easy access\n
◾ Excellent edge retention and corrosion resistance for durability and performance\n\n

⚫ Specification: \n

◾    BrandKATSU\n
◾    Weight3.36 ounces\n

</string>


</resources>
